Tony Nikolov

Senior Software Engineer

Email: anikolovn@gmail.com Contact number: 073 9800 4749

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/antonionikolov

Github: www.github.com/silkyfray

Personal Statement

A highly motivated, pragmatic fullstack engineer with excellent problem-solving skills. I have a passion for the industry and a deep appreciation for the complexity of software systems. I have worked to reach technical expertise and an ability to effectively communicate and collaborate in order to deliver great value to my clients. Available immediately.

Relevant Experience

Programming Languages — Working experience in Javascript, Typescript and C#. Previous experience in C++

Frontend Frameworks — Working experience in the React 16 ecosystem. Previous experience with Angular 5

Frontend Tools and Libraries — React, Angular, Mobx, Redux, GraphQL, ESLint, Mapbox, React-Intl, Storybook, Jest, Enzyme, Algolia, Gulp, Webpack, Styled Components, JSS, SASS

Backend Frameworks — Working experience with .NET Core 2. Previous experience with .NET Web Api 2, .NET ServiceStack, Nodejs

Databases — SQL, MongoDB, Event Sourcing

Project Support Tools — Git, Subversion, YouTrack, JIRA, Confluence, TeamCity, TFS, Docker

Project Management — SCRUM and Incremental methodology environments

Work Experience

Senior Software Contractor - Manchester, UK Laterooms - March 2019 to August 2019

I worked on the wizian platform behind <u>www.virgintrainsescapes.co.uk</u> and <u>holidays.nationalexpress.com</u> written in React and Redux.

Responsibilities:

- Develop, unit test and review React code.
- Write automated Cypress tests.
- Participate in the improvement of the platform architecture.
- Help and mentor junior developers.

Senior Software Engineer - iVendi, Manchester, UK May 2018 to Feb 2019

iVendi is a leader in providing online vehicle retailing solutions. I was fulfilling the role of a tech lead on a large project with an international bank, creating a vehicle marketplace to compete with mobile.de. I successfully bridged the gap between the development, product, test and UX teams to deliver a polished beta version ready to be presented to German dealers. I am the first line of support for technical issues and considerations.

I developed several modules for the project primarily in React. One of them was the translation pipeline to enable multi-lingual support. Using the *react-intl* library we are able to switch the language dynamically on the UI. The translations for all languages are kept in a master file and with node.js scripting we prepare json files ready to be consumed by the UI.

I also architected part of the CQRS backend service in .NET Core that stores events.

Responsibilities:

- Write and review code in a Typescript React, Mobx, .NET Core software stack deployed with TeamCity, Docker, Kubernetes, Rancher.
- Plan and prioritise development tasks from user stories on an agile kanban board.
- Lead and line manage a team of five developers.
- Conduct interviews for development positions.

Software Developer - Stratec Biomedical, Burton-on-Trent, UK January 2018 to May 2018

Stratec develop and manufacture automation solutions for life sciences.

Responsibilities:

- Architect and develop software using a Angular 4+, Web Api 2, T-SQL stack.
- Help establish new web development standards during a shift away from desktop application development.

Software Engineer - Automsoft, Dublin, Ireland May 2016 to December 2017

Automsoft's core product is an object database that processes time-series data from sensors and other manufacturing devices. I worked on the analytical and visualisation tools on top of that data.

Some of my accomplishment:

- Lead developer for the core backend features and a primary contributor on the frontend features of the new InfoModel product an abstraction layer over physical networks built using React/Redux/.NET. It provides modelling and visualisation tools improving the monitoring and reporting of these networks.
- Overhauled the security and user management spanning the whole product line. Secured server-to-server and client-to-server communication over HTTPS as well as incorporating stateless JWT tokens.
- Helped stabilise the codebase and finish the outstanding features of the visual Calculation Engine that is used for data transformation and analytics.
- Responsible for performing code reviews on both Junior and Senior developers, participating in the architectural design of new solution features, as well as training devs to use React.

Games Developer - Boon Studios, Dublin, Ireland June 2015 to February 2016

My duties at Boon consisted writing C++ and Objective-C code for mobile games.

- Developed cross-platform mobile games using C++ with the cocos-2dx game library.
- Managed the product lifecycle including development and release.
- Updated the monetisation platform and ported the code base from 32 bit to 64 bit for several small games.
- Developed Python scripts to ease the development process for their now well-acclaimed title Puzzle Gods.

Executive Officer (Internship) - Irish Revenue Commissioners, Dublin January 2014 to Aug 2014

Part of a team that developed full-stack web reporting applications. My technical responsibilities included UI prototyping, SQL database design, Java Spring back-end development, and testing the back-end of the applications on the production and staging servers. Heavily involved in the project planning, documentation, and release management

of the application.

Education

MSc in Computer Science - Trinity College Dublin 2014 to 2015

Graduated with Distinction.

Dissertation - "Volume Rendering Optimisations for Mobile Devices". The research examines multithreading approaches and graphics optimisations for 3D volume rendering.

BA (Mod) in Computer Science - Trinity College Dublin 2010 to 2014

Graduated with First Class Honours.

Interests and Hobbies

calisthenics, music, techno events, dancing, socialising, swimming, football, F1, gaming